

WAIS ABDULLAH

+62895323960818 | waisabdullah@outlook.com | www.linkedin.com/in/wais-abdullah

Tangerang, Banten, Indonesia

I am a recent graduate from the Biochemistry major with a deep understanding of the basic principles of biochemistry and practical experience in the laboratory. I am known as an individual who is consistent in my work, adaptable and disciplined. During my studies, I was active in research projects that required rigorous data analysis and the application of rigorous scientific methods. I have a high enthusiasm to continue learning and accepting new challenges, and am committed to contributing effectively and developing in the professional field. I am open to working in various fields that can utilize my skills and knowledge.

Education Level

Institut Pertanian Bogor - Bogor, Indonesia

Sep 2020 - Mar 2024

Bachelor Degree in Biochemistry, 3.55/4.00

 Awardee on G-Awarding Night 2022 held by Department of Science, Apreciation, and Achievment BEM FMIPA IPB 2022 (Nominated as Best Talented Artist in G-Awarding 2022)

Work Experiences

Surfactant and Bioenergy Research Center - Bogor, Indonesia

Jun 2022 - Jul 2022

Research Intern

- Project: Essential Oil Bioadditives to Improve the Quality and Performance of Biodiesel
- Biodiesel formulations B35 and B40 for the development of reducing the environmental impact of transportation fuels
- Determine the density and acid number of the biodiesel sample as a fundamental aspect in assessing its quality, characterizing it as a fuel, ensuring compliance with standards and optimizing production processes.
- Identify biogas samples using GC-MS to provides detailed information about the composition of biogas, facilitating its effective
 utilization, ensuring compliance with regulations, and contributing to ongoing research and development in the field of renewable
 energy and waste management.

Co-curricular Activites & Leadership

Community of Research and Education in Biochemistry (CREBs) IPB - Bogor, Indonesia

Dec 2021 - Nov 2022

Sports and Talent Division Staff

- Designing a talent development program for IPB biochemistry students related to sports and arts, impacting 50+ students
- Increasing the number of IPB biochemistry students' involvement in sports and arts activities through effective social media strategies, including interesting content, appropriate posting scheduling, and active interaction with students, impacting 100+ students

Biochemistry Champion League - Bogor, Indonesia

Jan 2022 - Oct 2022

General Secretary

- Supervise and provide direction to all divisions in the implementation of activities
- Manage administration of activities such as venue rental and event permits to ensuring legal compliance, public safety, efficient resource allocation, positive community relations, and overall success in organizing events.
- · Create proposals to help gain support, resources, and cooperation from the various stakeholders involved in the event.
- Create a timeline as a crucial step in the overall event management process, helping ensure efficiency, coordination, and success.

Lomba Karya Ilmiah Populer (LKIP) - Bogor, Indonesia

May 2021 - Oct 2022

Competition Division Staff

- Designing technical competition activities to enriches the learning experience, promotes practical application of knowledge, and prepares participants for the demands of their chosen fields.
- Processing competition score data as an integral to the fair evaluation, recognition of achievements, improvement of participants, and overall success and credibility of the competition.
- Recapitulate the competition scores as transparency, fairness, feedback, recognition, learning, record-keeping and accountability, all of which are important elements in driving successful and reputable competition.

Achievements, Skills & Other Experience

- Achievements (2019): 1st Place in category of Lomba Bidang Studi Kimia (LBSK) Ke-16 Universitas Tanjungpura 2019 (District level)
- Achievements (2019): 1st Place in category of Chemistry Competition Pekan Kimia 2019 (District level)
- Achievements (2019): 3rd Place in category of Chemistry in National Science Olympiad (District level)

- Achievements (2019): Participant in category of Chemistry in National Science Olympiad (Provincial)
- Hard Skills: Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Power Point)
- Hard Skills: Laboratory Analysis Instruments (Spectrofotometer UV-Vis/Microplate reader, HPLC, GC-MS)
- Hard Skills: Adobe PhotoshopHard Skills: Adobe Illustrator
- Hard Skills: Canva
- Hard Skills: SPSS Software
- **Projects** (2023): Determination of Total Phenolics, Flavonoids, α-Glucosidase Inhibition Activity of n-Hexane, Ethyl Acetate and Methanol Extracts of Red Betel (Piper crocatum)